Hello.
Welcome back.
And this lesson, we shall see how to configure our S.P.I for interrupt mode.
So we will do exactly what we did.
So come to connectivity S.P.I one.
I'm going to enable the US food most duplex over here.
And these will be a neighborhood for us.
Okay.
And then I'm just going to make sure our board works with most of the F four boats out.
I'm gonna change this to 16 so that I can get my EPB one timer clocks 60 and an APB to term a clock
16 as well so that those with the Air Force, you shouldn't have any difference.
Okay, now we can go to the, um, the configuration of the S.P.I.
And then I click over here, parameter sirtuins.
And this time we can reduce the frequency even further by getting a larger and larger pre-schooler o
use a pre-schooler such as this over here.
And we're doing this because we're using the um, we're using the interrupt.
And we don't want to sort of miss some of it.
We don't want to, uh.
Yeah.
Miss some of the data that comes.
So we reduce in the frequency drastically the frequency of the S.P.I.
And because and because we use an interrupt, we have to always enable the interrupt from the MVC certains
over here.
We can go ahead and generate our project or come over here.
I'll give the project to name.
I call this S.P.I as call interrupt and then, um, isolate it to change over here.
Skew the mix.
Click generate over here.
So those are projects we to do like we did before, we're going to create the Eriks buffer and a T Expo
for the T Expo for has the data.
It's going to transmit it.
And we expect to receive in the X buffer.
Right.
So we've defined it the same way the R X buffer starts off empty.
Once that is done, we can, um, use the same API, but this time would interrupt that we used earlier.
We use HARL S.P.I transmit, receive.
This time we're going to use Harlette, S.P.I crunch me to receive interrupt.
Let's do so.
I'm going to come down here after S.P.I has been initialized.
I'll see how underscore s.p.i.
And then on this call.
Transmit like this then.
And then receive.
And then over here I t for interrupt.
And then the first then is the address of the handle, the SBI handle which is H s.p.i one.
HSP won't like this.
And then the next is the um the Bufford has the data to be transmitted.
We call it this t x buffer.
And the next argument is the buffer to store the received data.
We call in this R X buffer.
And the data size, which is 10.
This time we don't need to pass the time out because we dealing with interrupt.
Right.
So n as you would know when we always dealing with interrupt.
We've got to find the callback function.
So let's do that now.
So we go to the module to find a callback.
I go to drive us over here.
And then source.
And then what I'm looking for is the S.P.I to see.
And then like we did.
We can do control F and find the weak keyword.
Because they always start with weak.
And what we're looking for is the um, transmit receive complete callback.
If we want to do a callback only when receive is complete.
We can take this one if we want.
Just transmit complete.
We can take the other one.
But we want both our 60 X callback.
So I'll copy this from over here.
I'll come to Main over here.
Then I'll paste this in here like this.
And everything in here is going to be wiped off like this.
Okay, so we have to delete that, we could cue it from here.
And over here, we don't need to do anything in the in the Kobuk if we have something to do.
We can put it here, but we don't have something to do.
So is our classic to something.
If you want to blink on LSD, you can blink an LCD.
We didn't set up the LCD, so this is classic.
Do something.
One other thing we can do is just put an infinite loop here that will do nothing.
Remember, this callback is only you know, the process only jumps here whenever this received, when
never you know this receive and transmit it s are 60 X.
So it doesn't mean we're going to be stuck here forever.
You know, it's a background thread.
Um, actually, I'll take this out.
Shouldn't be teaching.
This is not a good will front in this example.
If there is something we want to do here, we can, um, do it here.
Um, let's see.
Put a counter here and counter.
Then we can basically do counter.
Plus plus.
Plus plus here.
Okay.
Now we have something we can work with.
Remember we still um we still doing the loop back.
So you've got to connect the P seven and P six with a jumper wire to demonstrate this.
I'm going to click over here to build a close this this fully.
I'm gonna go to the debug click over here.
This one here.
And then okay, over here.
Over here, we still have a while.
Let's see.
We cannot break point here at home.
That's mean.
Just click over here.
We have a break point.
I'm going to add our counter to the Yum, to our expressions when two US will pull counter over here
like this when I click here to run.
It's, uh.
Um, oh, I ordered two expressions, I should be added to live expressions.
I'm going to clean this.
So I'm going to add I will counter over here two live expressions and I'm going to add our our expert
for here.
Remember, we've run once.
That is why we see an account to us was then.
This is our receive for Lissie.
And indeed, we've received the data.
We can try that again.
I'm going to relaunch, terminate and launch again.
Okay, it's Lodin.
AK.
And we still have a break point here.
Well, we have heard expression.
I'm going to click to run to see.
We have two other expressions again.
This is frustrating.
Stop this.
Oh, just remove all evil and then add our X buffer.
Oh, that will counter.
Which is up here.
I added our XPO for it.
I'm supposed to copy this.
Oh, you're supposed to copy this, sorry, but the computer is a bit slow.
OK, so we have come to one because we had just run again.
OK.
And then, um, I know you get a point so you can take out the count, uh, take out the jumper wire
and you realize that our console, our counter one to count is a duplicate of a counter won't count.
And then our our expert be empty.
So we like a mission in this hall.
S.P.I T XRX Complete Kobuk.
If you have a block of code that you want to execute, one of the SBA transmits and receives data.
This is where you do it.
Over here we simply count on a variable.
And equally, if you have a block of code that you want to execute only when data is received by the
SBI, such as you want to take that data and pass, pass it and pass, it could mean taken or taken
out spaces and commerce and created into something.
You can execute that in a callback as well.
Over here we just put in a counter.
So that's all the rage from any questions at all.
Just leave it in the questions area.
As you can see, the difference here is basically transmit to receive, which I t which means interrupt
and then you just need to put this callback function.
We can leave it empty if we want.
But it has to be here.
We can leave empty.
Right.
But I'm just using this opportunity to increment a counter and then, um.
Yeah.
Like we said, the S.P.I trick we are using here is a loop buck trick, um, such that our experiments
want to depend on a particular sleeve.
But later on we'll start dealing with some other peripherals that require S.P.I communication.
And you would see how practical the S.P.I setup is.
But this order is for now.
I'll see you later.